Now, I don't want you to get me wrong -- I absolutely understand the importance of ritual, especially when it comes to the people that we love. But we have to be able to create and practice this ritual without harming the environment, which is why we need new options. So let's return to the idea of protection, sanitation and beautification. We'll start with a dead body. The funeral industry will protect your dead body by offering to sell your family a casket made of hardwood or metal with a rubber sealant. At the cemetery, on the day of burial, that casket will be lowered into a large concrete or metal vault. We're wasting all of these resources -- concretes, metal, hardwoods -- hiding them in vast underground fortresses. When you choose burial at the cemetery, your dead body is not coming anywhere near the dirt that surrounds it. Food for worms you are not. Next, the industry will sanitize your body through embalming: the chemical preservation of the dead. This procedure drains your blood and replaces it with a toxic, cancer-causing formaldehyde. They say they do this for the public health because the dead body can be dangerous, but the doctors in this room will tell you that that claim would only apply if the person had died of some wildly infectious disease, like Ebola. Even human decomposition, which, let's be honest, is a little stinky and unpleasant, is perfectly safe. The bacteria that causes disease is not the same bacteria that causes decomposition. Finally, the industry will beautify the corpse. They'll tell you that the natural dead body of your mother or father is not good enough as it is. They'll put it in makeup. They'll put it in a suit. They'll inject dyes so the person looks a little more alive -- just resting. Embalming is a cheat code, providing the illusion that death and then decay are not the natural end for all organic life on this planet. Now, if this system of beautification, sanitation, protection doesn't appeal to you, you are not alone. There is a whole wave of people -- funeral directors, designers, environmentalists -- trying to come up with a more eco-friendly way of death. For these people, death is not necessarily a pristine, makeup, powder-blue tuxedo kind of affair. There's no question that our current methods of death are not particularly sustainable, what with the waste of resources and our reliance on chemicals. Even cremation, which is usually considered the environmentally friendly option, uses, per cremation, the natural gas equivalent of a 500-mile car trip. So where do we go from here? Last summer, I was in the mountains of North Carolina, hauling buckets of wood chips in the summer sun. I was at Western Carolina University at their "Body Farm," more accurately called a "human decomposition facility." Bodies donated to science are brought here, and their decay is studied to benefit the future of forensics. On this particular day, there were 12 bodies laid out in various stages of decomposition. Some were skeletonized, one was wearing purple pajamas, one still had blonde facial hair visible. The forensic aspect is really fascinating, but not actually why I was there. I was there because a colleague of mine named Katrina Spade is attempting to create a system, not of cremating the dead, but composting the dead. She calls the system "Recomposition," and we've been doing it with cattle and other livestock for years. She imagines a facility where the family could come and lay their dead loved one in a nutrient-rich mixture that would, in four-to-six weeks, reduce the body -- bones and all -- to soil. In those four-to-six weeks, your molecules become other molecules; you literally transform. How would this fit in with the very recent desire a lot of people seem to have to be buried under a tree, or to become a tree when they die? In a traditional cremation, the ashes that are left over -- inorganic bone fragments -- form a thick, chalky layer that, unless distributed in the soil just right, can actually hurt or kill the tree. But if you're recomposed, if you actually become the soil, you can nourish the tree, and become the post-mortem contributor you've always wanted to be -- that you deserve to be. So that's one option for the future of cremation. But what about the future of cemeteries? There are a lot of people who think we shouldn't even have cemeteries anymore because we're running out of land. But what if we reframed it, and the corpse wasn't the land's enemy, but its potential savior? I'm talking about conservation burial, where large swaths of land are purchased by a land trust. The beauty of this is that once you plant a few dead bodies in that land, it can't be touched, it can't be developed on -- hence the term, "conservation burial." It's the equivalent of chaining yourself to a tree post-mortem -- "Hell no, I won't go! No, really -- I can't. I'm decomposing under here." (Laughter) Any money that the family gives to the cemetery would go back into protecting and managing the land. There are no headstones and no graves in the typical sense. The graves are scattered about the property under elegant mounds, marked only by a rock or a small metal disk, or sometimes only locatable by GPS. There's no embalming, no heavy, metal caskets. My funeral home sells a few caskets made out of things like woven willow and bamboo, but honestly, most of our families just choose a simple shroud. There are none of the big vaults that most cemeteries require just because it makes it easier for them to landscape. Families can come here; they can luxuriate in nature; they can even plant a tree or a shrub, though only native plants to the area are allowed. The dead then blend seamlessly in with the landscape. There's hope in conservation cemeteries. They offer dedicated green space in both urban and rural areas. They offer a chance to reintroduce native plants and animals to a region. They offer public trails, places for spiritual practice, places for classes and events -- places where nature and mourning meet. Most importantly, they offer us, once again, a chance to just decompose in a hole in the ground. The soil, let me tell you, has missed us. I think for a lot of people, they're starting to get the sense that our current funeral industry isn't really working for them. For many of us, being sanitized and beautified just doesn't reflect us. It doesn't reflect what we stood for during our lives. Will changing the way we bury our dead solve climate change? No. But it will make bold moves in how we see ourselves as citizens of this planet. If we can die in a way that is more humble and self-aware, I believe that we stand a chance. Thank you. (Applause)
Pero no quiero que me malinterpreten, entiendo totalmente la importancia del ritual, sobre todo cuando se trata de la gente que amamos. Pero tenemos que poder crear y practicar este ritual sin dañar el ambiente, por lo que necesitamos nuevas opciones. Así que volvamos a la idea de protección, saneamiento y embellecimiento. Empezaremos con un cadáver. La industria funeraria protegerá su cadáver ofreciendo vender a su familia un ataúd de madera dura o metal con un sellador de caucho. En el cementerio, el día del entierro, ese ataúd será bajado a una gran bóveda de hormigón o metal. Estamos desperdiciando estos recursos - hormigón, metal, maderas duras - ocultándolos en vastas fortalezas subterráneas. Cuando uno elige el entierro en el cementerio, el cadáver no llega a ninguna parte en la tierra que lo rodea. Alimento para gusanos, no serán. Luego, la industria desinfectará el cuerpo mediante embalsamamiento: la preservación química de los muertos. Este procedimiento drena la sangre y la sustituye por un formaldehído cancerígeno, tóxico. Dicen que lo hacen por la salud pública porque el cadáver puede ser peligroso, pero los médicos de esta sala les dirán que esto solo sería así si la persona hubiera muerto de alguna enfermedad infecciosa, como el Ébola. Incluso la descomposición humana que, seamos honestos, es un algo apestoso y desagradable, es perfectamente segura. Las bacterias que causan enfermedad no son las mismas bacterias que causan descomposición. Por último, la industria embellecerá el cadáver. Dirá que el cadáver natural de tu madre o de tu padre no es bueno tal como es. Le pondrá maquillaje. Le pondrá un traje. Le inyectará tintes para que la persona parezca un poco más viva... solo descansa. El embalsamamiento es un truco que da la ilusión de que la muerte y la decadencia no son el fin natural de la vida orgánica en el planeta. Si este sistema de embellecimiento, saneamiento y protección no les gusta, no están solos. Hay toda una serie de gente - directores de funerarias, diseñadores, ambientalistas - que tratan de llegar a una manera de morir más ecológica. Para estas personas, la muerte no es necesariamente un tema de maquillaje y un traje azul impecable. No hay duda, nuestros actuales métodos de muerte no son particularmente sostenibles, el desperdicio de recursos y nuestra confianza en los productos químicos. Incluso la cremación, que generalmente se considera la opción ecológica, usa, por cada cremación, el equivalente en gas natural de un viaje en auto de 800 km. Entonces, ¿hacia dónde vamos? El verano pasado, estaba en las montañas de Carolina del Norte, transportando baldes de astillas de madera bajo el sol estival. Estuve en Western Carolina University en su "granja de cuerpos", más exactamente llamada "instalación de descomposición humana". Se traen aquí los cuerpos donados a la ciencia y se estudia su decadencia en beneficio del futuro de la medicina forense. En este día en particular, había 12 cuerpos dispuestos en diversas etapas de descomposición. Algunos eran esqueletos, uno tenía un pijama púrpura, uno aún tenía vello facial rubio visible. El aspecto forense es realmente fascinante, pero no era esa la razón por la que estaba allí. Estaba allí porque una colega llamada Katrina Spade intenta crear un sistema, no para cremar muertos, sino para el compostaje de muertos. Denomina "Recomposición" al sistema, y lo hemos hecho con ganado y otros animales durante años. Ella imagina una instalación donde la familia podría ir a poner a su muerto amado en una mezcla rica en nutrientes que, de cuatro a seis semanas, reduciría los huesos del cuerpo y todo... a tierra. En esas cuatro a seis semanas, sus moléculas se convierten en otras moléculas; literalmente se transforman. ¿Cómo encajaría esto con el deseo muy reciente que muchas personas parecen tener de ser enterrados bajo un árbol, o convertirse en árbol al morir? En una cremación tradicional, las cenizas que quedan - fragmentos óseos inorgánicos - forman una capa gruesa y calcárea que, a menos que se distribuya en el suelo de manera adecuada, puede dañar o matar al árbol. Pero si se recompone, si uno vuelve a la tierra, puede nutrir al árbol, y volverse el colaborador post mortem que siempre quiso ser... que uno merece ser. Esa es una opción para el futuro de la cremación. Pero ¿y el futuro de los cementerios? Hay mucha gente que piensa que ya no deberíamos tener cementerios porque nos estamos quedando sin tierra. Pero, ¿qué pasa si lo reenmarcamos, y vemos al cadáver no como el enemigo de la tierra, sino como su potencial salvador? Estoy hablando de entierros de conservación, donde un fideicomiso compra grandes extensiones de tierra. La belleza de esto es que una vez que uno pone cadáveres en esa tierra, no puede tocarse, no se puede construir allí, de ahí el término "enterramiento de conservación". Es el equivalente de encadenarse a un árbol post mortem... "¡Diablos, no, no iré! No, de verdad... no puedo. me estoy descomponiendo por aquí". (Risas) El dinero que la familia da al cementerio volvería a la protección y a la gestión de la tierra. No hay lápidas ni tumbas en el sentido típico. Las tumbas están dispersas por la propiedad bajo montículos elegantes, marcados solo por una roca o un pequeño disco de metal, o a veces ubicables solo por GPS. No hay embalsamamiento, ni ataúdes de metal, pesados. Mi funeraria vende algunos ataúdes de sauce tejido y bambú. Pero honestamente, la mayoría de las familias elige un sudario simple. No tiene las grandes bóvedas que requieren la mayoría de los cementerios porque les facilita ser parte del paisaje. Las familias pueden venir aquí; pueden disfrutar la naturaleza; incluso pueden plantar un árbol o un arbusto, aunque solo se permiten plantas nativas. Los muertos se integran a la perfección con el paisaje. Hay esperanza en los cementerios de conservación. Ofrecen espacio verde dedicado en zonas urbanas y rurales. Ofrecen la oportunidad de reintroducir flora y fauna nativas a una región. Ofrecen senderos públicos, lugares para práctica espiritual, lugares para clases y eventos, lugares donde confluyen el duelo y la naturaleza. Más importante, nos ofrecen, una vez más, una oportunidad de descomponernos en un agujero en la tierra. La tierra, les diré, nos ha echado de menos. Pienso que mucha gente está empezando a darse cuenta de que la industria funeraria actual no los satisface. Para muchos de nosotros, que nos desinfecten y embellezcan no nos refleja. No refleja lo que defendimos durante nuestras vidas. ¿El cambio en la forma de enterrar los muertos resolverá el cambio climático? No. Pero hará movimientos audaces en nuestras formas de vernos como ciudadanos de este planeta. Si podemos morir de una manera más humilde y autoconsciente, creo que tenemos una oportunidad. Gracias. (Aplausos)